<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>David Trejo | Developer and Consultant</title>
  <subtitle>DTrejo's Developer Tips</subtitle>
  <id>https://dtrejo.com/</id>
  <link href="https://dtrejo.com/"/>
  <link href="https://dtrejo.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-04-23T21:54:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>DTrejo</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Reliably Get Your Team to Write Articles for Your Engineering Blog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-reliably-get-your-team-to-write-articles-for-your-engineering-blog.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//how-to-reliably-get-your-team-to-write-articles-for-your-engineering-blog.html</id>
    <published>2017-04-23T21:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-04-23T21:54:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You probably already know why it's so helpful to have your team write
engineering articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They're massively useful for recruiting, even if only a few people read them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If many people read your articles, you'll get tons more applicants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you sell to developers, your articles create trust and lead to more
  sales, on top of the above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-do-you-get-an-engineer-to-write-an-article"&gt;How do you get an engineer to write an article?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don't. Instead you ask them over email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"How does X work?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip is from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/melindakjacobs"&gt;Melinda Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of
&lt;a href="https://www.lucentsky.com/"&gt;Lucent Sky&lt;/a&gt;. Her company automatically finds
vulnerabilities in your code and fixes many of them (which is
great for banks who have so many vulnerabilities that their security teams can't
possibly fix them all manually &lt;code&gt;:)&lt;/code&gt;. Thanks Melinda!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, ask an engineer on your team and you'll get a detailed explanation of how some
part of your product works.  If you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; they left out something impressive, ask
again after their initial answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"I was really impressed with your work on Y, can you explain how that works too?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you take their answers, &lt;a href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-write-consistently-painlessly-and-without-writers-block.html#when-youre-ready-to-start-editing-these-writing-tools-will-come-in-handy"&gt;edit them with these tips&lt;/a&gt;,
run it by them to see if they have any suggestions, and publish. If
you're an engineer like me, I'd recommend you don't let them make the edits
themselves–they may get hung up on them. Instead ask them for feedback over email
or in a quick read-through and make the changes for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's up to you to make remember to ask your team to write articles after they
finish interesting projects. Remember, to an outsider, boring projects can be
just as interesting because they demonstrate mature, boring
technology&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;. Projects with large business impact are also very
interesting, especially to engineers who care about business results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a minute right now to add a link to this article in your sprint
retrospectives (or planning cycle retrospectives). Otherwise you may forget to
put this advice into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="a-published-article-is-worth-more-than-1000-unpublished-articles"&gt;A published article is worth more than 1,000 unpublished articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on the article until you're 80% happy with it, then publish it. If you're
being ruthless with yourself, one hour total invested in the article is a
reasonable timeline. If you have extreme difficulty with a particular sentence,
the easiest way to fix it is to delete it &lt;code&gt;:)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-does-melindas-method-work-well"&gt;Why does Melinda's method work well?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People write emails in complete sentences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People write like they speak, meaning it reads more naturally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People rarely have writer's block when it comes to explaining things to coworkers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People love to be recognized for their work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's it, good luck!&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS Do you have an engineering hiring tip you'd like me write up? Email me: david att dtrejo dot com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;† Boring Technology, for example &lt;a href="http://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology"&gt;Choose Boring Technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology-slides"&gt;(slides)&lt;/a&gt; by Dan McKinley, Founder at Skyliner;
&lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/dianachow/marty-weiner-reddit-cto-sxswi-2016-everythings-harder-at-scale/1"&gt;"The boring tech revolution is here"&lt;/a&gt; by Reddit CTO Marty Weiner;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/yoshuawuyts/tiny-guide-to-non-fancy-node"&gt;Non-fancy Node&lt;/a&gt; by Yoshua Wuyts, author of 372 node modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why share salary?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/why-share-salary.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//why-share-salary.html</id>
    <published>2017-04-12T18:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-04-12T18:53:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sharing salary ranges for engineering positions is delicate. You don't want
candidates to see the top end of the range and think that they left money on the
table. This creates awkwardness and unmet expectations. You also don't want
current engineers to feel they are being underpaid, making them ask for a raise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sharing-salary-ranges-is-beneficial-because"&gt;Sharing salary ranges is beneficial because…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job posts with salary get 75% more clicks than those that don't.&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineers will love you for it, which means way more applicants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You won't waste thousands of dollars on interviews with candidates who you can't afford.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You differentiate yourself from underpaying employers and the legion of shitty startups (there's way more of these than you realize). You might think that in today's climate, no respectable startup would lowball solid candidates. Your candidates have no idea whether you're respectable. The burden is on you to demonstrate respectability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sharing salary is "you-focused." If you appear selfish and only talk about what your company needs, everyone will tune out. Readers only care about themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You won't melt into the sea of recruiter emails which almost never have salary information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You catch the attention of undervalued engineers who are great at what they do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may already be publishing salary ranges to some job sites, so you might as
well share the range on your site as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="youre-still-hesitant-about-sharing-salary-bands"&gt;You're still hesitant about sharing salary bands…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some options to reduce risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List a few salary ranges so it's clear you're hiring junior/mid/senior people. This way, the junior person won't expect to earn at the top end of the range.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test it: run two identical job descriptions, one with a salary range and one without. See which gets more applicants and interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List only the bottom end of the range. Listing only the minimum could backfire because people may expect you to pay only +$20,000.00 USD above the minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do compensation research to learn about what the market pays. Work the numbers backwards from how much revenue you want them to make you (for this, I made you &lt;a href="https://EngineerWorth.com"&gt;EngineerWorth.com&lt;/a&gt;). When you have a solid business case for the hire, you'll feel good about the range you end up sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's stopping you from sharing salary ranges? Email me and tell me: david åt dtrejo dot com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;† &lt;a href="https://blog.stackoverflow.com/2016/07/salary-transparency/"&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Massive List of Engineering Recruiting Channels</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/massive-list-of-engineering-recruiting-channels.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//massive-list-of-engineering-recruiting-channels.html</id>
    <published>2017-03-28T06:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-28T06:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="this-list-is-for-you-if"&gt;This list is for you if…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don't have enough top-of-funnel engineering candidates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You want to pursue channels with higher quality candidates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You'd like channels where you can attract engineers rather than chasing them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You want to hire engineers from under-represented groups in technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave it to you to figure out how to source from each of these channels. I've
sorted to the top the channels for which I am comfortable sharing my conversion
rates with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="massive-list-of-all-hiring-channels"&gt;Massive list of all hiring channels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cold emails to engineers (50% reply-rate and 17% interested in a call is achievable with a well-written email)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email newsletters – for example js weekly, node weekly, ruby weekly, and so on for your whole stack (2% click through rate is achievable with a well-written ad)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HN who's hiring monthly (#5 post with 30 applicants/month is achievable with a well-written post)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Airbnb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angellist – A-list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootcamp grads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;California layoffs notifications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conference tours (keynote or give a talk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conferences – lanyrd: speakers, attendees, sponsors can email attendees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contest for e.g. 1 set of free conference tickets to Velocity for example (very expensive but cool!); and 1 set of free tickets for under-represented group in tech. Also worth including: housing, for example on a not creepy teammate's couch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coursera grads
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;e.g. with certs from…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/algorithms"&gt;Algorithms Specialization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/progfun1"&gt;Functional Programming Principles in Scala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning"&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/algorithms-on-graphs"&gt;Algorithms on Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Craigslist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Events: print index cards with the short blurb of your open positions and give them to your team to put up in the women's/gender-neutral/men's bathroom stalls and urinals. Give them tape.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook graph search for CS grads who are friends of friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook groups for your area: hackathon groups, new to the bay area, new grad $gradyear, breaking into tech, job searching, technical interviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For yourself and each teammate…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Facebook friends&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: contributors to your OSS repos&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: issue-openers on your OSS repos&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: star-ers of your OSS repos&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Google contacts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Twitter lead cards&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Twitter: your followers; people you follow; people they follow; people who follow your competitors; people your competitors follow.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;University alumni facebook groups; email lists; in-person events&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;University professors who recommend you their top students&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;University recruiting: resume reviews; give tech talks; give unofficial tech talks; visit unofficially&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;University student group email lists; official paid recruiting programs; facebook groups; etc&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;University hackathons&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Games: advertising inside of various games, ideally with &amp;gt;50% ratio of women via Willem Wijnans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: OSS contribs to OSS projects you admire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: people who open issues on OSS projects you admire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github/BitBucket: people who star OSS projects you admire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goodreads/Amazon: friends of people who've reviewed eng books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goodreads/Amazon: people who've reviewed engineering books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Plus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hackathons: attending them, contacting past winners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HackerRank.com, LeetCode.com, Interviewing.io, projecteuler.net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hired&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HN articles about your stack + interesting eng decisions - authors, commenters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HN who's searching for a job&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instagram: hashtags, geotags&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IRC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linkedin: traditional searches (ew); email your friends who you'd want to work with again; email friends who know many of your target type of engineer and ask for intros. I made a tool to help you do this, email me about it, I'll run it for you for free :) (david [åt] dtrejo dot com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Livecoding on Twitch, liveedu.tv, YouTube,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meetups:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;meetup.com;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;artisanal meetup websites&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;your own meetups (e.g. start organizing your city's offline first meetup)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;arrive prepared: know roughly who you want to talk to&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium articles about your technologies - authors, commenters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium articles exposing bad workplaces - authors, commenters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product Hunt – product creators who don't seem to have solid business models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quora answerers for technologies in your stack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reddit – people who share their absurdly low salary and impressive achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reddit r/programming and every other relevant r/ -&amp;gt; Post engineering articles with CTA (call to action).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reddit, monthly who's hiring for each language you use (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/C_Programming/comments/5w9z8i/whos_hiring_c_programmers_q1_2017/df41v4h/"&gt;r/C_Programming&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Referrals: Searchlight meetings aka sourcing sessions (used at Stripe, Dropbox, and more. via Ivan Kirigin list ways to get them, link to searchlight instructions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retargeted ads using emails you've found elsewhere (discount by # of people who run ad-blockers)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skype search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skype search (via Atallah)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slack groups that are public: hamsterpad, slacklist, chitchats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snapchat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spotify: spell your message with songs via Willem Wijnans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;StackExchange Data Explorer via Willem Wijnans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stackoverflow answerers for technologies in your stack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Startups in general because they underpay their engineers and give out equity that is more illiquid than typical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Startups who haven't publicly raised in the last year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strava&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://philipmorganconsulting.com/lead-generation-trust-velocity/"&gt;Trust Velocity via Philip Morgan&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mainstream press&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Media interview&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Podcast guesting (combined with great CTA)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Single guest post on major publication&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lead magnet on trusted 3rd party website&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Regularly showing up in prospect's email inbox with relevant content&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;"Lumpy Envelope" campaign (e.g. how Matasano gives books to candidates who aren't experienced enough yet)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Job aid, calculator&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Udemy grads (https://www.udacity.com/hire-talent) - free to hire
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;e.g. with certs from…&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/design-of-computer-programs--cs212"&gt;Design of Computer Programs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/intro-to-algorithms--cs215"&gt;Intro to Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/computability-complexity-algorithms--ud061"&gt;Computability, Complexity &amp;amp; Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vimeo – speakers, commenters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volunteering events – e.g. teaching kids to code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WiFi SSID via Willem Wijnans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write a book for engineers (personal experience: works great)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Youtube – speakers, maybe commenters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would make this list more useful for you? Email me: david [åt] dtrejo dot com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May engineers be with you,&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- PS Learn exactly how I hire: enter your email below. --&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chaos in Your Product Prototyping</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/chaos-in-your-product-prototyping.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//chaos-in-your-product-prototyping.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-17T04:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-17T04:50:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;strong&gt;I no longer believe that product ideas should be &lt;em&gt;validated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; One should only
build after one has pre-sold or collected signed letters of intent to buy at
a specific price-point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this for the rest of the team at Neo, where we built new lines of
business for Fortune 500 companies. Our projects were 12 weeks long. We
designed, built, and launched new products for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is an amalgamation of tactical advice, written for teams of at least one
designer and one engineer who want to build a new product more quickly. It can
be applied to building a new feature as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-is-chaos"&gt;What is Chaos?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's this strange feeling that you're not as productive as you could be because
the flow of work and coordination and communication with your team is not at its
best. It's the feeling that you are occasionally doing inefficient things, or
that you don't know what's going to happen next, or taking steps backward. Your
"chaos" as an engineer is different from that of a designer, something to be
aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="areas-of-chaos"&gt;Areas of Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design flow – flow of a design from whiteboard to code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment choice – given what's already been built, your team's decision on what fidelity the next experiment should be&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out the definition of "MVP"&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out what the "MVP" is for this solution space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="reducing-chaos"&gt;Reducing Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we explain each area of chaos, along with some ways to reduce chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="less-chaos-design-flow"&gt;Less Chaos: Design Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an engineer, it's difficult to know when to jump in and code. Has the design
undergone enough feedback from users? Is it at a high-enough fidelity? Will the
design change drastically soon? Is there a major flaw that won't be noticed
until it gets coded up? These are difficult questions to answer–I'll outline a
full flow, and then I'll outline an "ideal" flow that might help us move faster
on future designs. Having this conversation with Alex (designer of the project)
was very helpful for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each bolded step includes some feedback from the Engineer, if needed. And
possibly feedback from another Neo designer, but not too much! Too much feedback
leads to more chaos. Advice can make you regress to a previous step in the flow,
and it takes much longer to finish it. Also, not all advice is worth taking even
though it may be "better," so you may have done yourself a disservice. It all
depends on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="full-flow"&gt;Full Flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whiteboard the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper prototype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put design into proto.io or invisionapp.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a psd of the design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fast-flow"&gt;Fast flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whiteboard the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Co-worker feedback (3 people)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put design into proto.io or invisionapp.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback, co-worker feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a psd of the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="you-really-should"&gt;You really should…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include real copy in the design(s)–this can change information hierarchy, the
sizes of page elements, what design works or doesn't work, etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider choosing standard widths and sizes for your code and design. Alex and
I chose the following: 1rem = 16px, and the height/width/spacing of
everything on the page is a multiple 16px, or 8px. This makes coding the page
much easier. Don't forget that line-height is not the same as the top of the
letter "M", this means not every number in your design/code will be pretty (b/c
CSS typography doesn't directly map to visual beauty: Ask Gon for more
information about this, he can draw you a picture to show you what I mean).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="less-chaos-experiment-choice"&gt;Less Chaos: Experiment Choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to choose the next experiment. It is difficult to assess how
"confident" you are about the product. Are you truly confident enough to build
the MVP right now? Here's the rough progression of experiments that eventually
help you get comfortable enough to build the MVP. It is expected that you will
run an experiment, it will fail, and you could return even to the first few
bullet points! I don't recommend choosing to validate two ideas at once. Ask and
share common conversion numbers for each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Optional] Find/Validate the problem
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do customer development and figure out what their problems are&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Figure out which is the most painful&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find/Validate the solution to the problem
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Come up with solutions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do customer development to see which one people want more, discounted by the fact that customer's don't always know what they want&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a lean canvas on the top problems, eliminating the ones that don't have good ROI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do customer development on the remaining most-painful problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a landing page for the problem, drive traffic to it. 
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;e.g. fit experiment: Adwords CTR: 0.54%, email signup conversion: 24.5%; Style experiment: Adwords CTR: 0.19% email signup conversation: 10.17%&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a concierge MVP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make an MVP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a real Product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optionally A/B tests if you have enough traffic, to improve the copy/product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acquire more and more users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Success!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="less-chaos-mvp-choice"&gt;Less Chaos: MVP Choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is hard. No way around it. Think about it for a really long time. Here's a list of ways you can make your product simpler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut down on your audience until it is only one person
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. women, in the bay area, buying pants, and only plus-sizes. Jane Doe.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut down to only one value prop
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. "I want to know how it will fit and look on someone like me": show variously sized models in the same pair of pants&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do things by hand, only program at the last moment, use spreadsheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliver less product less often
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. we will send you one look (on four different models) every week&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only one problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only one solution to one problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only something you could do yourself manually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only what you can get done in 7 days / 100 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="client-gotchas"&gt;Client Gotchas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's really best to 100% ignore the fact that your client has an existing
audience. You certainly can send an email to a segment of their audience, but
this will take weeks to make happen and won't make a significant difference to
whether people use/need your product. Your other acquisition channels should
already be working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wakeupmrkim"&gt;Alex Kim&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gonzif"&gt;Gon Zifroni&lt;/a&gt;, and everyone else at Neo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Get Your Business to Pull You Forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-get-your-business-to-pull-you-forward.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//how-to-get-your-business-to-pull-you-forward.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-11T04:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-11T04:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For me, there are two major reserves of energy. Drawing on &lt;strong&gt;grind energy&lt;/strong&gt;
drains you until you complete the task. The small hit of dopamine upon
completion rarely feels worth it. You use grind energy to complete tedious but
necessary tasks that you don't particularly enjoy. &lt;strong&gt;Pull energy&lt;/strong&gt; is how you
feel when you look forward to the work and can't stop yourself from starting on
it (and maybe even completing it!). Pull energy gives you joy and makes your
work feel like play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="all-of-my-best-work-has-been-done-under-the-influence-of-pull-energy"&gt;All of my best work has been done under the influence of pull energy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this article is to pick out the situations which created pull, so I can
replicate them more consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've read about different kinds of authors, and there is a parallel
between those who meticulously plan their book (grind) vs those who let it flow out of
them fully formed (pull).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="work-which-pulled-me-that-i-could-not-resist-doing"&gt;Work which pulled me, that I could not resist doing:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote a book for a client in ~2 weeks. Why? Had executed on the subject matter multiple times; client had already paid for it and needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote ~50 pages of advice for computer science students in a few evenings. Why? I had posted an ask-me-anything in a facebook group. I had multiple students asking me specific questions who all needed my advice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote a book for computer science students in ~3 weeks. Why? I'd posted again in the facebook group and many students wanted the book. I'd already written the first pass of the material (above), and I also had another chapter on negotiation applied to job offers that was jumping to get out of me (because I knew students needed it so badly).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://dtrejo.com/lazytemplating"&gt;https://dtrejo.com/lazytemplating&lt;/a&gt; in an evening. Why? I saw a co-worker hand-editing massive copy-pasted HTML blobs in a tiny wordpress editor window, and making mistakes constantly. He wasn't an engineer so he needed an easy way to do string templating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://dtrejo.com/streak-view"&gt;https://dtrejo.com/streak-view&lt;/a&gt; in a few sessions. Why? Viewing my sales pipeline in my inbox was destroying my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished reading good business books in only 1-2 days. Why? They were well-written and also taught me skills I knew I needed to improve (usually consulting/marketing/sales).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The new sales page for my 2nd niche. Why? As a result of sales calls I had a deepened understanding of my prospects and needed to better express what my service was about, so that I could feel better about offering it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://engineerworth.com"&gt;https://engineerworth.com&lt;/a&gt;. Why? I knew people were undervaluing their engineering time and needed a more accessible rule of thumb for calculating ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I've also been pulled by any work that I've dreamt about in a pleasant way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="do-you-see-the-pattern-someone-had-paid-me-asked-for-my-help-or-i-felt-the-pain-myself"&gt;Do you see the pattern? Someone had paid me, asked for my help, or I felt the pain myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can I create more pull energy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get more people to ask for my help, within my niche.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get more people to pre-pay me for work I haven't done yet, but only when all the material is already in my head, and needs a good reason to flow out onto paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not preferable: experience pain first-hand, and give in to the desire to automate or delegate it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage in work where &lt;strong&gt;one unit of action&lt;/strong&gt; results in &lt;strong&gt;one unit of outcome&lt;/strong&gt;. It's no wonder video games are so popular: you put in the work and then you actually succeed (idea via Amy Hoy). For example, when you answer someone's question, you've made that person happy, and you've also simultaneously written a new article, newsletter installment, or forum post which will help even more people and attract them to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-do-we-create-virtuous-cycles-of-pull-energy-that-never-run-out"&gt;How do we create virtuous cycles of pull energy that never run out?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best work is work you can't resist doing. The best marketing is marketing you
can't resist doing. The best money is money you couldn't resist making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say content marketing takes 6 months to kick in. You may not realize it when you first start, but you're probably going to spend at least 12 months trying to make your niche work. It is worth starting right away, but how do we may writing enjoyable? I haven't taken Amy Hoy's 30x500, but I have read Year Of Hustle and both Jonathan Stark and Philip Morgan have told me how much they look forward to speaking to their audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-id-create-pull-for-myself-in-my-next-business"&gt;How I'd create pull for myself in my next business:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice this is almost exactly what Amy recommends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very low amount of grind activation energy is needed to begin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Monitor the watering holes at which my niche audience gathers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Answer questions that are posed in my audience's watering holes, with email list call to action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Use my answers to write articles (with email list CTA).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Use my answers to email my list (with "buy or pre-order my product or service" CTA).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: When I get replies from email list readers, answer their questions and use the answers for more articles, newsletters, and potentially book material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: People pay you for your product/book or ask for your consulting help.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have set up the preceding virtuous cycle, you can repeat it with new products and services, and only include CTAs to what people haven't already bought. This idea is Brennan's. Brennan: thanks for coming over for steak before I'd even begun solo-consulting and recommending that I read The Brain Audit (my #2 favorite book); Getting Everything You Can Out of Everything You've Got (partially read); The Sticking Point Solution (unread still); Influence (unread still); and Inc Yourself (partially read). I really enjoyed the Double Your Freelancing Rate book (née The Blueprint).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above compares very favorably to my main strategy for making sales, cold outreach emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Building a target list of names and researching their emails.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Writing an email outreach sequence. It's only pull if… you've read the good marketing books; know how to write cold emails; and know what your prospects desire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Cleaning and loading your target list's contact details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Minor) Grind: Loading your email sequence into a tool like Quickmail. If you didn't use a tool, the grind of following up on first emails would kill you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Following up after they've replied and each answer requires a custom reply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Scheduling a sales call (thank you calendly.com!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Getting on sales calls that you've scheduled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Modifying your latest proposal to fit a new client.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Your client pays you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy has said that she and Alex Hillman have spent loads of time figuring out how to get 30x500 students to actually finish the course. I imagine they figured out how to break the process of building a business into stacking bricks which each give well-defined satisfaction and accomplishment (I stole and maybe warped her analogy :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="remove-grind-from-your-life"&gt;Remove grind from your life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself: what's painful? Then ask yourself if you can delegate it, buy a tool/book/service to help you, or quit altogether (and renegotiate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have high expectations for yourself, you'll frequently need to quit certain work and renegotiate with &lt;strong&gt;yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; Why? The tyrant dictator part of your brain is pushing you to grind out work that is so low ROI or doomed to fail that your gut rebels. Then the rest of your brain notices your gut, catches up, and realizes it has to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="grind-that-you-should-remove-from-your-life"&gt;Grind that you should remove from your life:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contracts (use a lawyer or get paid 100% up front)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accounting (use an accountant and have a friend teach you the basics of book-keeping–thanks Samir!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything a virtual assistant could do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ideally: anything that's not a crucial source of revenue for you and your business. My crucial sources of revenue are writing, copywriting (cold emails, proposals, sales pages), and coding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding when it's not for yourself and no one has paid you yet. Even if you are coding for yourself, you'd better only be doing it for you, for fun, and not for money. Pre-sell first! More easily said than done.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Sales and Discovery Process: this is why tripwires and Roadmapping sessions work so well. They shift the energy balance from just you, to both you and your client (because they've paid for something small).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="go-forth-and-create-a-virtuous-cycle-of-energy-creation-in-your-business"&gt;Go forth and create a virtuous cycle of energy creation in your business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thoughts on this would be much appreciated. What virtuous cycles drive your business? What virtuous cycles drive your personal life‡? My email is david å† dtrejo.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://expensiveproblem.com"&gt;Jonathan Stark&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://taskdrive.com"&gt;Samir Said&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://philipmorganconsulting.com"&gt;Philip Morgan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://doubleyourfreelancing.com/"&gt;Brennan Dunn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://unicornfree.com/"&gt;Amy Hoy, Alex Hillman&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://marcusblankenship.com/"&gt;Marcus Blankenship&lt;/a&gt; for their writing and advice. &lt;a href="http://peterlyons.com/"&gt;Peter Lyons&lt;/a&gt;, thanks for listening so closely this morning and saying it was insightful :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‡ I offer to cook for my friends' dinner parties. I go to and get invited to WAY more dinner parties :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Overcome Cold-Email Procrastination</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/overcome-cold-email-procrastination.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//overcome-cold-email-procrastination.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-04T20:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-04T20:16:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's child's play for me to write &amp;amp; send sequences on behalf of my clients. When I write for myself, I struggle. This article is meant to help future me, the next time I'm cold emailing for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="desired-outcomes-of-this-checklist"&gt;Desired Outcomes of This Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="procrastinate-as-little-as-possible-while-putting-together-your-list-and-sequence"&gt;1) Procrastinate as little as possible while putting together your list and sequence.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="feel-good-about-your-progress-from-the-moment-youve-started-and-never-get-stuck"&gt;2) Feel good about your progress from the moment you've started, and never get stuck&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="send-to-your-1st-prospect-as-soon-as-possible-starting-the-virtuous-cycle-between-your-effort--replies--sales-calls--new-business--cashed-checks"&gt;3) Send to your 1st prospect as soon as possible, starting the virtuous cycle between your effort &amp;lt;&amp;gt; replies &amp;lt;&amp;gt; sales calls &amp;lt;&amp;gt; new business &amp;lt;&amp;gt; cashed checks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the following list and pick the easiest ones. Do the ones that feel easy to you. Check them off as you go. Don't do them in order. The idea is not to do all of these. It's to do &lt;strong&gt;anything at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sequence-writing"&gt;Sequence Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write 1 email, in gmail, to 1 prospect. Don't send it. Instead, load it into Quickmail, and start a sequence on that solitary prospect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write 1 email step, and continue writing email steps as long as they flow from your fingers. Stop once they stop flowing. Don't force them out. Write to only one person. Don't try to write to both CTOs and CEOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="list-building"&gt;List-Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick your 1st customer or your highest grossing customer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google for lists of their competitors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask Fancyhands to find emails for all of their competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="list-cleaning"&gt;List-Cleaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate the different types of prospects that you researched. Don't fall prey to the temptation to write one email sequence that works for more than one type of prospect!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean 1 prospect. Add them to your sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="amazing-work-youve-sent-your-1st-quickmail-to-your-1st-prospect"&gt;Amazing work, you've sent your 1st Quickmail to your 1st prospect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to celebrate. Great, now it's time to send you second email. You're probably stressing right now about how you want to say something slightly different. That's okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="handling-infinite-variations"&gt;Handling Infinite Variations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clone the old variation as a new variation that's exactly the same in Quickmail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pause the old variation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete the sections of the old variation that you want to customize and replace them with variables. Gotcha: make sure to add them as custom variables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your spreadsheet, make new columns to match the new variables, and &lt;strong&gt;put what you deleted from the old emails into every single cell of the corresponding column.&lt;/strong&gt; These are your defaults, for when you're too lazy to customize and want to send anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For this second prospect, customize the appropriate columns to match what you want to say.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preview that prospect by searching for their name in Quickmail, then click sequences, then choose your sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looks good? Send it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voila!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you've sent to two people, and you're equipped to make any edits you want without messing up emails you've sent to past prospects. And you didn't have to make the decision to throw out any past writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep repeating the above process until you're done with all your prospects. Or, send to them with the defaults, that's perfectly okay too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;br /&gt;
EngineerOverflow.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS &lt;strong&gt;Want exact instructions on how to ask all your friends for referrals using Quickmail?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://gum.co/CSGETMONEY"&gt;Buy my book&lt;/a&gt;. The referrals chapter also includes the exact sequence I used. It's a considerate 2-step sequence and got me 30% reply-rate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
