<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>David Trejo | Developer and Consultant</title>
  <subtitle>DTrejo's Developer Tips</subtitle>
  <id>https://dtrejo.com/</id>
  <link href="https://dtrejo.com/"/>
  <link href="https://dtrejo.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-02-17T04:50:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>DTrejo</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Chaos in Your Product Prototyping</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/chaos-in-your-product-prototyping.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//chaos-in-your-product-prototyping.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-17T04:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-17T04:50:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;strong&gt;I no longer believe that product ideas should be &lt;em&gt;validated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; One should only
build after one has pre-sold or collected signed letters of intent to buy at
a specific price-point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this for the rest of the team at Neo, where we built new lines of
business for Fortune 500 companies. Our projects were 12 weeks long. We
designed, built, and launched new products for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is an amalgamation of tactical advice, written for teams of at least one
designer and one engineer who want to build a new product more quickly. It can
be applied to building a new feature as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-is-chaos"&gt;What is Chaos?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's this strange feeling that you're not as productive as you could be because
the flow of work and coordination and communication with your team is not at its
best. It's the feeling that you are occasionally doing inefficient things, or
that you don't know what's going to happen next, or taking steps backward. Your
"chaos" as an engineer is different from that of a designer, something to be
aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="areas-of-chaos"&gt;Areas of Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design flow – flow of a design from whiteboard to code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment choice – given what's already been built, your team's decision on what fidelity the next experiment should be&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out the definition of "MVP"&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out what the "MVP" is for this solution space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="reducing-chaos"&gt;Reducing Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we explain each area of chaos, along with some ways to reduce chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="less-chaos-design-flow"&gt;Less Chaos: Design Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an engineer, it's difficult to know when to jump in and code. Has the design
undergone enough feedback from users? Is it at a high-enough fidelity? Will the
design change drastically soon? Is there a major flaw that won't be noticed
until it gets coded up? These are difficult questions to answer–I'll outline a
full flow, and then I'll outline an "ideal" flow that might help us move faster
on future designs. Having this conversation with Alex (designer of the project)
was very helpful for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each bolded step includes some feedback from the Engineer, if needed. And
possibly feedback from another Neo designer, but not too much! Too much feedback
leads to more chaos. Advice can make you regress to a previous step in the flow,
and it takes much longer to finish it. Also, not all advice is worth taking even
though it may be "better," so you may have done yourself a disservice. It all
depends on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="full-flow"&gt;Full Flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whiteboard the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper prototype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put design into proto.io or invisionapp.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a psd of the design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fast-flow"&gt;Fast flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whiteboard the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Co-worker feedback (3 people)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put design into proto.io or invisionapp.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback, co-worker feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a psd of the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE the design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="you-really-should"&gt;You really should…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include real copy in the design(s)–this can change information hierarchy, the
sizes of page elements, what design works or doesn't work, etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider choosing standard widths and sizes for your code and design. Alex and
I chose the following: 1rem = 16px, and the height/width/spacing of
everything on the page is a multiple 16px, or 8px. This makes coding the page
much easier. Don't forget that line-height is not the same as the top of the
letter "M", this means not every number in your design/code will be pretty (b/c
CSS typography doesn't directly map to visual beauty: Ask Gon for more
information about this, he can draw you a picture to show you what I mean).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="less-chaos-experiment-choice"&gt;Less Chaos: Experiment Choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to choose the next experiment. It is difficult to assess how
"confident" you are about the product. Are you truly confident enough to build
the MVP right now? Here's the rough progression of experiments that eventually
help you get comfortable enough to build the MVP. It is expected that you will
run an experiment, it will fail, and you could return even to the first few
bullet points! I don't recommend choosing to validate two ideas at once. Ask and
share common conversion numbers for each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Optional] Find/Validate the problem
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do customer development and figure out what their problems are&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Figure out which is the most painful&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find/Validate the solution to the problem
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Come up with solutions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do customer development to see which one people want more, discounted by the fact that customer's don't always know what they want&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a lean canvas on the top problems, eliminating the ones that don't have good ROI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do customer development on the remaining most-painful problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a landing page for the problem, drive traffic to it. 
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;e.g. fit experiment: Adwords CTR: 0.54%, email signup conversion: 24.5%; Style experiment: Adwords CTR: 0.19% email signup conversation: 10.17%&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a concierge MVP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make an MVP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a real Product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optionally A/B tests if you have enough traffic, to improve the copy/product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acquire more and more users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Success!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="less-chaos-mvp-choice"&gt;Less Chaos: MVP Choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is hard. No way around it. Think about it for a really long time. Here's a list of ways you can make your product simpler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut down on your audience until it is only one person
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. women, in the bay area, buying pants, and only plus-sizes. Jane Doe.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut down to only one value prop
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. "I want to know how it will fit and look on someone like me": show variously sized models in the same pair of pants&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do things by hand, only program at the last moment, use spreadsheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliver less product less often
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;E.g. we will send you one look (on four different models) every week&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only one problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only one solution to one problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only something you could do yourself manually&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only what you can get done in 7 days / 100 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="client-gotchas"&gt;Client Gotchas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's really best to 100% ignore the fact that your client has an existing
audience. You certainly can send an email to a segment of their audience, but
this will take weeks to make happen and won't make a significant difference to
whether people use/need your product. Your other acquisition channels should
already be working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wakeupmrkim"&gt;Alex Kim&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gonzif"&gt;Gon Zifroni&lt;/a&gt;, and everyone else at Neo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Get Your Business to Pull You Forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-get-your-business-to-pull-you-forward.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//how-to-get-your-business-to-pull-you-forward.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-11T04:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-11T04:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For me, there are two major reserves of energy. Drawing on &lt;strong&gt;grind energy&lt;/strong&gt;
drains you until you complete the task. The small hit of dopamine upon
completion rarely feels worth it. You use grind energy to complete tedious but
necessary tasks that you don't particularly enjoy. &lt;strong&gt;Pull energy&lt;/strong&gt; is how you
feel when you look forward to the work and can't stop yourself from starting on
it (and maybe even completing it!). Pull energy gives you joy and makes your
work feel like play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="all-of-my-best-work-has-been-done-under-the-influence-of-pull-energy"&gt;All of my best work has been done under the influence of pull energy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this article is to pick out the situations which created pull, so I can
replicate them more consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've read about different kinds of authors, and there is a parallel
between those who meticulously plan their book (grind) vs those who let it flow out of
them fully formed (pull).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="work-which-pulled-me-that-i-could-not-resist-doing"&gt;Work which pulled me, that I could not resist doing:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote a book for a client in ~2 weeks. Why? Had executed on the subject matter multiple times; client had already paid for it and needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote ~50 pages of advice for computer science students in a few evenings. Why? I had posted an ask-me-anything in a facebook group. I had multiple students asking me specific questions who all needed my advice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote a book for computer science students in ~3 weeks. Why? I'd posted again in the facebook group and many students wanted the book. I'd already written the first pass of the material (above), and I also had another chapter on negotiation applied to job offers that was jumping to get out of me (because I knew students needed it so badly).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://dtrejo.com/lazytemplating"&gt;https://dtrejo.com/lazytemplating&lt;/a&gt; in an evening. Why? I saw a co-worker hand-editing massive copy-pasted HTML blobs in a tiny wordpress editor window, and making mistakes constantly. He wasn't an engineer so he needed an easy way to do string templating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://dtrejo.com/streak-view"&gt;https://dtrejo.com/streak-view&lt;/a&gt; in a few sessions. Why? Viewing my sales pipeline in my inbox was destroying my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finished reading good business books in only 1-2 days. Why? They were well-written and also taught me skills I knew I needed to improve (usually consulting/marketing/sales).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The new sales page for my 2nd niche. Why? As a result of sales calls I had a deepened understanding of my prospects and needed to better express what my service was about, so that I could feel better about offering it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrote &lt;a href="https://engineerworth.com"&gt;https://engineerworth.com&lt;/a&gt;. Why? I knew people were undervaluing their engineering time and needed a more accessible rule of thumb for calculating ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I've also been pulled by any work that I've dreamt about in a pleasant way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="do-you-see-the-pattern-someone-had-paid-me-asked-for-my-help-or-i-felt-the-pain-myself"&gt;Do you see the pattern? Someone had paid me, asked for my help, or I felt the pain myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can I create more pull energy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get more people to ask for my help, within my niche.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get more people to pre-pay me for work I haven't done yet, but only when all the material is already in my head, and needs a good reason to flow out onto paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not preferable: experience pain first-hand, and give in to the desire to automate or delegate it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage in work where &lt;strong&gt;one unit of action&lt;/strong&gt; results in &lt;strong&gt;one unit of outcome&lt;/strong&gt;. It's no wonder video games are so popular: you put in the work and then you actually succeed (idea via Amy Hoy). For example, when you answer someone's question, you've made that person happy, and you've also simultaneously written a new article, newsletter installment, or forum post which will help even more people and attract them to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-do-we-create-virtuous-cycles-of-pull-energy-that-never-run-out"&gt;How do we create virtuous cycles of pull energy that never run out?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best work is work you can't resist doing. The best marketing is marketing you
can't resist doing. The best money is money you couldn't resist making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say content marketing takes 6 months to kick in. You may not realize it when you first start, but you're probably going to spend at least 12 months trying to make your niche work. It is worth starting right away, but how do we may writing enjoyable? I haven't taken Amy Hoy's 30x500, but I have read Year Of Hustle and both Jonathan Stark and Philip Morgan have told me how much they look forward to speaking to their audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-id-create-pull-for-myself-in-my-next-business"&gt;How I'd create pull for myself in my next business:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice this is almost exactly what Amy recommends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very low amount of grind activation energy is needed to begin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Monitor the watering holes at which my niche audience gathers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Answer questions that are posed in my audience's watering holes, with email list call to action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Use my answers to write articles (with email list CTA).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Use my answers to email my list (with "buy or pre-order my product or service" CTA).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: When I get replies from email list readers, answer their questions and use the answers for more articles, newsletters, and potentially book material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: People pay you for your product/book or ask for your consulting help.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have set up the preceding virtuous cycle, you can repeat it with new products and services, and only include CTAs to what people haven't already bought. This idea is Brennan's. Brennan: thanks for coming over for steak before I'd even begun solo-consulting and recommending that I read The Brain Audit (my #2 favorite book); Getting Everything You Can Out of Everything You've Got (partially read); The Sticking Point Solution (unread still); Influence (unread still); and Inc Yourself (partially read). I really enjoyed the Double Your Freelancing Rate book (née The Blueprint).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above compares very favorably to my main strategy for making sales, cold outreach emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Building a target list of names and researching their emails.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Writing an email outreach sequence. It's only pull if… you've read the good marketing books; know how to write cold emails; and know what your prospects desire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Cleaning and loading your target list's contact details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Minor) Grind: Loading your email sequence into a tool like Quickmail. If you didn't use a tool, the grind of following up on first emails would kill you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Following up after they've replied and each answer requires a custom reply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Scheduling a sales call (thank you calendly.com!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Getting on sales calls that you've scheduled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind: Modifying your latest proposal to fit a new client.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull: Your client pays you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy has said that she and Alex Hillman have spent loads of time figuring out how to get 30x500 students to actually finish the course. I imagine they figured out how to break the process of building a business into stacking bricks which each give well-defined satisfaction and accomplishment (I stole and maybe warped her analogy :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="remove-grind-from-your-life"&gt;Remove grind from your life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself: what's painful? Then ask yourself if you can delegate it, buy a tool/book/service to help you, or quit altogether (and renegotiate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have high expectations for yourself, you'll frequently need to quit certain work and renegotiate with &lt;strong&gt;yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; Why? The tyrant dictator part of your brain is pushing you to grind out work that is so low ROI or doomed to fail that your gut rebels. Then the rest of your brain notices your gut, catches up, and realizes it has to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="grind-that-you-should-remove-from-your-life"&gt;Grind that you should remove from your life:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contracts (use a lawyer or get paid 100% up front)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accounting (use an accountant and have a friend teach you the basics of book-keeping–thanks Samir!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything a virtual assistant could do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ideally: anything that's not a crucial source of revenue for you and your business. My crucial sources of revenue are writing, copywriting (cold emails, proposals, sales pages), and coding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding when it's not for yourself and no one has paid you yet. Even if you are coding for yourself, you'd better only be doing it for you, for fun, and not for money. Pre-sell first! More easily said than done.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Sales and Discovery Process: this is why tripwires and Roadmapping sessions work so well. They shift the energy balance from just you, to both you and your client (because they've paid for something small).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="go-forth-and-create-a-virtuous-cycle-of-energy-creation-in-your-business"&gt;Go forth and create a virtuous cycle of energy creation in your business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your thoughts on this would be much appreciated. What virtuous cycles drive your business? What virtuous cycles drive your personal life‡? My email is david å† dtrejo.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://expensiveproblem.com"&gt;Jonathan Stark&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://taskdrive.com"&gt;Samir Said&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://philipmorganconsulting.com"&gt;Philip Morgan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://doubleyourfreelancing.com/"&gt;Brennan Dunn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://unicornfree.com/"&gt;Amy Hoy, Alex Hillman&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://marcusblankenship.com/"&gt;Marcus Blankenship&lt;/a&gt; for their writing and advice. &lt;a href="http://peterlyons.com/"&gt;Peter Lyons&lt;/a&gt;, thanks for listening so closely this morning and saying it was insightful :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‡ I offer to cook for my friends' dinner parties. I go to and get invited to WAY more dinner parties :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Overcome Cold-Email Procrastination</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/overcome-cold-email-procrastination.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//overcome-cold-email-procrastination.html</id>
    <published>2016-10-04T20:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-04T20:16:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's child's play for me to write &amp;amp; send sequences on behalf of my clients. When I write for myself, I struggle. This article is meant to help future me, the next time I'm cold emailing for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="desired-outcomes-of-this-checklist"&gt;Desired Outcomes of This Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="procrastinate-as-little-as-possible-while-putting-together-your-list-and-sequence"&gt;1) Procrastinate as little as possible while putting together your list and sequence.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="feel-good-about-your-progress-from-the-moment-youve-started-and-never-get-stuck"&gt;2) Feel good about your progress from the moment you've started, and never get stuck&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="send-to-your-1st-prospect-as-soon-as-possible-starting-the-virtuous-cycle-between-your-effort--replies--sales-calls--new-business--cashed-checks"&gt;3) Send to your 1st prospect as soon as possible, starting the virtuous cycle between your effort &amp;lt;&amp;gt; replies &amp;lt;&amp;gt; sales calls &amp;lt;&amp;gt; new business &amp;lt;&amp;gt; cashed checks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the following list and pick the easiest ones. Do the ones that feel easy to you. Check them off as you go. Don't do them in order. The idea is not to do all of these. It's to do &lt;strong&gt;anything at all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sequence-writing"&gt;Sequence Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write 1 email, in gmail, to 1 prospect. Don't send it. Instead, load it into Quickmail, and start a sequence on that solitary prospect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write 1 email step, and continue writing email steps as long as they flow from your fingers. Stop once they stop flowing. Don't force them out. Write to only one person. Don't try to write to both CTOs and CEOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="list-building"&gt;List-Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick your 1st customer or your highest grossing customer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google for lists of their competitors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask Fancyhands to find emails for all of their competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="list-cleaning"&gt;List-Cleaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate the different types of prospects that you researched. Don't fall prey to the temptation to write one email sequence that works for more than one type of prospect!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean 1 prospect. Add them to your sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="amazing-work-youve-sent-your-1st-quickmail-to-your-1st-prospect"&gt;Amazing work, you've sent your 1st Quickmail to your 1st prospect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to celebrate. Great, now it's time to send you second email. You're probably stressing right now about how you want to say something slightly different. That's okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="handling-infinite-variations"&gt;Handling Infinite Variations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clone the old variation as a new variation that's exactly the same in Quickmail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pause the old variation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete the sections of the old variation that you want to customize and replace them with variables. Gotcha: make sure to add them as custom variables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In your spreadsheet, make new columns to match the new variables, and &lt;strong&gt;put what you deleted from the old emails into every single cell of the corresponding column.&lt;/strong&gt; These are your defaults, for when you're too lazy to customize and want to send anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For this second prospect, customize the appropriate columns to match what you want to say.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preview that prospect by searching for their name in Quickmail, then click sequences, then choose your sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looks good? Send it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voila!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you've sent to two people, and you're equipped to make any edits you want without messing up emails you've sent to past prospects. And you didn't have to make the decision to throw out any past writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep repeating the above process until you're done with all your prospects. Or, send to them with the defaults, that's perfectly okay too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;br /&gt;
EngineerOverflow.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS &lt;strong&gt;Want exact instructions on how to ask all your friends for referrals using Quickmail?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://gum.co/CSGETMONEY"&gt;Buy my book&lt;/a&gt;. The referrals chapter also includes the exact sequence I used. It's a considerate 2-step sequence and got me 30% reply-rate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Write Consistently, Painlessly, and Without Writer's Block</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-write-consistently-painlessly-and-without-writers-block.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//how-to-write-consistently-painlessly-and-without-writers-block.html</id>
    <published>2016-07-04T04:41:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-04T04:41:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The more of these you do, the more successful your writing session will be. I've marked the most important ones with a ★.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;★ Write in the morning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;★ Close your eyes while you type&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not edit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not reference your research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have your research done the day before you sit down to write.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;★ Write into &lt;a href="http://750words.com"&gt;http://750words.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave the 750words.com tab open even after you finish for the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it fullscreen so you're less easily distracted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disconnect your internet, or write on a plane, or outside (even if it's cold: this gives you a natural deadline).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write about whatever you feel like; once that's poured out, you can move on to whatever "productive" writing you wanted to do. This is also known as writing out the "noise."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list of tips is built from experience and Josh Seiden's article, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/neo-innovation-ideas/how-to-write-a016e5d898bc"&gt;How to Write&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="when-youre-ready-to-start-editing-these-writing-tools-will-come-in-handy"&gt;When you're ready to start editing, these writing tools will come in handy.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;★ &lt;a href="http://polishmywriting.com"&gt;http://polishmywriting.com&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite, despite its looks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;★ &lt;a href="http://hemingwayapp.com"&gt;http://hemingwayapp.com&lt;/a&gt; is great for simplifying sentences. If you're doing sales writing, get it under grade 8 to increase conversion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://alexjs.com/#demo"&gt;http://alexjs.com/#demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://labs.foxtype.com/politeness"&gt;http://labs.foxtype.com/politeness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grammarly.com"&gt;http://grammarly.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paperrater.com/free_paper_grader"&gt;http://paperrater.com/free_paper_grader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How To Email</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/how-to-email.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//how-to-email.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-29T22:51:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-29T22:51:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You think you know how to email. Think again. This is a guide on how to write and send emails that are considerate to the reader, and &lt;strong&gt;get replies&lt;/strong&gt;. This is meant for everyday people sending normal emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="be-considerate"&gt;Be considerate.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first email to someone, keep it under 250 words. How do you feel when people stop you on the street, then talk on and on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ask-only-one-question-directly-before-your-signature"&gt;Ask only one question, directly before your signature.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can only expect the reader to do one thing. Ask for it. If there's no question in an email, the reader has no reason to reply. If you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to, and you're already in conversation with someone, and you have more than one question you need answered, number your questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="so-you-want-them-to-reply"&gt;So you want them to reply?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it easy to reply. Make your reader's life effortless. Ask a single yes/no question. Provide choices of times to meet, or send them a Calendly link so you both save on back-and-forth email scheduling hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="extra-credit-show-you-did-your-research"&gt;Extra Credit: Show you did your research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell them what you know about them. If you're asking for help, detail the ways you tried to solve the problem on your own. Showing you've made an effort makes people feel that you are more relevant to them, and worth emailing back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the things that I see people getting wrong the most often. If you fix these in your emails, your readers will love you and you'll love yourself, because people will reply to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;br /&gt;
David&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS And when you care enough that you actually want a reply… ALWAYS &lt;a href="http://blog.close.io/follow-up"&gt;http://blog.close.io/follow-up&lt;/a&gt;. Especially do this if you are emailing a relative or someone who has agreed to help you: they are busy, but they do want to help—there's no way you can get on their bad side by being persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How I Can Help You</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dtrejo.com/help.html"/>
    <id>https://dtrejo.com//help.html</id>
    <published>2015-11-13T02:36:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-13T02:36:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>DTrejo</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What follows is a mix of simpler and more difficult things you can ask me about for advice. This is not a list of services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#software-engineering"&gt;Software Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#college-admissions-consulting"&gt;College Admissions Consulting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#consulting"&gt;Consulting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#writing"&gt;Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#sales"&gt;Sales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#marketing"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#food"&gt;Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#self-care"&gt;Self Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#other"&gt;Other&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="software-engineering"&gt;Software Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding callbacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding how to avoid callback hell by using named functions, and async.parallel/series for the rest of the cases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning what constitutes idiomatic node code (modularity, good abstraction, etc. Best learned via code review)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advising you on what modules to use so you get work done faster by using other people's code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coding conventions that will help you avoid errors such as uncalled callbacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting up / trying out browserify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting up / trying out stylus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As an inactive contributor to &lt;code&gt;mranney/node_redis&lt;/code&gt;, if you have any questions it's likely that I can help (can tell you about distributed systems, what redis is good for, what the other nosql's are good for, and am slightly familiar with the &lt;code&gt;node_redis&lt;/code&gt; codebase)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to use git like it's easy — rebase, manage branches, take pull requests quickly, use git's reflog to undo a git command that went wild and screwed up all your work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to break into software engineering if you just learned to code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to run a software engineering intern program&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good ways to recruit at Brown, both officially and unofficially&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to value equity (hint: 0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to figure out if a startup is good to work for&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to negotiate your salary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How all money is made on the internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to learn to code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to make a two-sided marketplace with Paypal API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use the Google Calendar and Youtube API from node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to choose colors for your site if you suck at color&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use a pull request checklist to increase the quality of your code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use a deploy checklist for less risky deploys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open Book Management&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Microsoft's academic papers about A/B testing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="college-admissions-consulting"&gt;College Admissions Consulting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get more students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to schedule workshops at local high-schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get a Yelp review taken down in under 12 hours if you're lucky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="consulting"&gt;Consulting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to write a proposal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to ask for referrals (and when)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get an amazing testimonial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get your first client(s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get paid from day 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to raise your rates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to organize and run your sales process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to choose a niche&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to research a new service offering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to convince your clients that a roadmapping session is an important first step prior to custom engineering work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to work to work your best with a designer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to test your value prop with content marketing using "the problem post." also helps you do customer development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to do respectful professional intros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to give a good handshake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How payment before starting work helps both you and the client be more successful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Managing the Professional Service Firm&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Book Yourself Solid&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How to Measure Anything&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Inc Yourself&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="writing"&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to write great cold emails to drive calls with buyer/decider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to write a sales page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to write your resume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to write to your value and outcomes, not simply your action and movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sales"&gt;Sales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to do outbound sales with cold emails in a way that works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puppy dog sales technique (don't feel salesy on the call, yet still make a sale eventually if it makes sense)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to design a sales page by stealing from a massive list of examples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many times to follow up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to keep track of your prospects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get anyone's email&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Predictable Revenue&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pricing with Confidence&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Barking up a Dead Horse&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How to Ask for the Moon and Get it&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="marketing"&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to choose a good name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to position yourself in the space of alternatives to your product or service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use drip campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get 17% more conversion on your AdWords &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; lots of effort&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to improve your SEO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Brain Audit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Positioning Manual for Technical Firms&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My Life in Advertising&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Positioning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="food"&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to make amazing steak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to make arepas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to take care of your chef's knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to take care of your cast iron pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="self-care"&gt;Self Care&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to get work done with a sense of accomplishment and eliminate multitasking by organizing yourself with a Kanban board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to give yourself a second brain with notational.net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to fix your hands if you coded too much&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who to talk to for style advice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to know if you are getting mildly depressed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to know if you are sleeping enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to know if you are drinking enough water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to decide what kind of lifestyle you want and work back from there to decide what you want to do with your life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to actually work out: join a class and make friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to easily swallow vitamins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to not get razor burn, not cut yourself, and get a way better shave with a safety razor and proper technique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to not get cavities: no sugar/carbs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Trigger Point Workbook&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Body by Science&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="other"&gt;Other&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to buy a road bike&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What you should do to get your kid into Brown (where I went)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to not hate noisy parties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How divorce is not so bad for your kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you should read…
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How to Ask for the Moon and Get it&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learned Optimism&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fooled by Randomness&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send me an email about any of these, I'd be happy to discuss it with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br /&gt;
David Trejo&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
